RESUME

NILESH BOROLE

Email id: nilesh30490@gmail.com **Mobile no:** +91-9967213720

Location: Pune

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nborole

Seeking a leadership role melding technical expertise for organizational growth, merging hands-on development with team leadership. 14 years of experience in building and scaling apps, aiming for an architectural position to guide a tech team towards company goals.

Technical Skills:

Languages	Java, Hacklang/PHP, J2EE, SQL.
Web Development	Angular JS, Bootstrap, NodeJS.
Framework	Eclipse Vert.x, MyBatis, Spring, Spring Boot, Spring Al.
Monitoring Tools	NewRelic, Grafana, AWS CloudWatch, Loggly, ELK.
Relational Databases	Vitess, MySQL, Oracle 11g.
NoSQL & NewSQL	VoltDB, Redis(Clustered), Apache Ignite, Apache HBase, MongoDB,
	Apache Hadoop.
Java Build Tools	Apache Maven.
Other	Reactive Programming, AWS Cloud, Docker, Kubernetes , Flutter,
	Generative AI, Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) & MCP.

Work Experience (14 Years)

1. Slack (Acquired by Salesforce) as Principal Member of Technical Staff(PMTS) from Oct 2021 to till now.

Role: Product Development Team member at Slack, overseeing modules such as billing, growth projects, calendar, email & third party integration. Technically leading a team of 14 engineers (12 backend, 2 Frontend).

Contributions:

- Leading third party integrations project into slack: File, Emails & Calendar integration.
- Worked on architecturing and designing of AI powered Slack Email App (3rd party integration).
- Architected the Slack Al add-on provisioning flow for enterprise customers.
- Led an enterprise provisioning automation project, linking with Salesforce, leading to a **30% revenue growth**.
- Optimized fair billing module, reducing calculation time by 8x for billions of users.
- Simplified country-specific tax configurations, removing engineer intervention needs.
- Led architecture of calendar features in email/calendar integration.
- Enhanced job queue architecture, enabling monitoring & alerting for distributed job execution.
- In essence, I oversee modules, guide projects, mentor teams, and lead cross team technical initiatives, contributing significantly to optimization, automation, revenue growth, and architectural advancements within Slack's product development landscape.

2. DebugsBunny as a Co-Founder & CTO from Mar 2020 to Sep 2021.

Role: Lead a technology team at DebugsBunny, an online teaching platform for K12 students focused on coding concepts.

Responsibilities:

- Created the initial MVP to assess product-market fit.
- Guided the tech stack selection and platform architecture decisions.
- Acted as a Java Backend Developer and Flutter Mobile App Developer.
- Engaged in discussions with teachers, content creators, and sales teams to gather feature requirements and steer product development.
- Assessed feature feasibility from a business and implementation standpoint.

In summary, I spearheaded the technology team at DebugsBunny, overseeing the MVP creation, technology decisions, Java backend development, Flutter-based Android app creation, and collaborating across teams to gather requirements and assess feature feasibility for effective product development.

3. Dream11 as a Platform Architect from Dec 2017 to Feb. 2020.

Role: Platform Team Member focused on scalability, technology research, and application enhancement. Leading team of 8 backend engineers.

Contributions:

- Architected and led 'Contest Service', boosting 10x+ write/read throughput for a service (12k write RPS).
- Led the design and implementation of a scalable 'Wallet Service' to handle high throughput of **100k writes RPS**.
- Developed a reactive framework with Eclipse Vert.x for micro-services, enhancing performance and responsiveness, used in 20+ microservices.
- Introduced 'Join Contest using Queue' feature, increasing contest join rate and revenue by 40%.
- Designed 'Fantasy Tour' and 'Contest Personalization' services, leveraging Eclipse Vert.x, Aerospike, Apache Ignite, and Amazon Aurora for scalability, high availability, and personalization based on user properties.

Overall, my contributions have significantly improved scalability, responsiveness, and revenue generation for Dream11, enhancing services through optimized architecture, reactive frameworks, and personalized features for users.

4. Interactive Brokers as a Software Engineer from July 2016 to Dec 2017.

At Interactive Brokers I was a part of the clearing team and worked as an individual contributor which handles Clearing System operations, a part of the trading platform.

5. MedStudio Pvt. Ltd. as Tech Lead from Feb. 2015 to July 2016

MedStudio is a product development organization that provides solutions in the healthcare domain. I was the first engineer to build the product from scratch, provision, and deploy the application on the Google cloud. I was involved in scaling application from 0 to 100k requests per day.

- 6. Zycus Infotech Pvt. Ltd. as Associate Tech Lead from Sept. 2013 to Jan 2015
- 7. Indian Research & Consultancy Center (IRCC), IIT-Bombay as Project Assistant from Nov. 2012 to Sept. 2013
- 8. **L&T Infotech** as Software Test Engineer from Aug. 2011 to Oct. 2012.

Qualification:

- 1. Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology from Fr. Conceicao Rodrigues Institute of Technology, Vashi Affiliated to Mumbai University- 63.7% (2011).
- 2. Passed 12th (HSC), from Birla College of Arts, Commerce and Science, Kalyan (2007) 82%.

I do hereby declare that the particulars of information and facts stated herein above are true, correct and complete to the best of my knowledge and belief.

NILESH ASHOK BOROLE